Collection of Maps of Los Angeles, California, the United States, and the World LSC.0294
UCLA Library Special Collections
Maps Collection of Los Angeles, California, the United States, and the World
circa 1516-1960
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0294
204 oversize folders
The collection consists of maps of Los Angeles and other parts of the United States including: California Geological Survey maps, tract maps of the San Francisco Bay area, beach cities of Southern California, New Mexico oil fields, maps from the American Civil War, railroad map of California, California gold fields, the Ranchos of Los Angeles and California city street maps. The collection also contains world maps and maps of other countries.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942327523606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of maps of Los Angeles, other parts of the United States, and various places in the world. Includes maps of California, California Geological Survey maps, tract maps of the San Francisco Bay area, beach cities of Southern California, New Mexico oil fields, maps from the 1860s concerning the American Civil War, railroad map of California, California gold fields, the Ranchos of Los Angeles, California city street maps, Mexico, South America, Caribbean, Russia, Australia, Pacific islands, Africa, India, Asia Minor, Middle East, Orient, Great Britain and Ireland, Western Europe, and world maps.
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Maps of Los Angeles, California, the United States and the World (86 items).
The same digitized items are also avaailable through the Calisphere portal: Maps of Los Angeles, California, the United States and the World (86 items).
- [Online Items]
  - [Undated]
    - Map of the subdivision of the Rancho Santa Ysabel and adjacent lands, San Luis Obispo Co., California, undated (Folder 100)
    - Map of the Centinela and Sausal Redondo ranches in Los Angeles County, Cal., undated (Folder 121)
    - Map of Los Angeles and vicinity: featuring Redondo Beach, undated (Folder 125)
  - [1695]
    - Amérique septentrionale divisée en ses principales parties, ou sont distingués les vns des autres les estats suivant quils appartiennent presentement aux François, Castillans, Anglois, Suedois, Danois, Hollandois, tirée des relations de toutes ces nations, 1695 (Folder 49)
  - [1700s]
    - De Californie et du nouveau Mexique, 1700 (Folder 65)
    - La Californie ou Nouvelle Caroline: teatro do los trabajos, Apostolicos de la Compa. e Jesus en la America Septe., 1720 (Folder 66)
  - [1800-1850]
    - United States and additions: 1820, 1821 (Folder 51)
    - Carta general para las navegaciones a la India Oriental por el mar del sur y el grande oceano que separa el continente americano del asiatico, 1825 (Folder 48)
    - Map of an exploring expedition to the Rocky Mountains in the year 1842 and to Oregon and North California in the years 1843-44, 1844 (Folder 56)
    - Map of an exploring expedition to the Rocky Mountains in the year 1842 and to Oregon and North California in the years 1843-44, 1845 (Folder 183)
    - Miltiary reconnassance of the Arkansas, Rio del Norte, and Rio Gila, 1847 (Folder 183)
    - Map of Mexico, including Yucatan and Upper California, exhibiting the chief cities and towns, the principal travelling routes, etc.; and, Map of the principal roads from Vera Cruz and Alvarado to the city of Mexico, including the Valley of Mexico, mountians, plains, volcanoes, lakes, etc., 1847 (Folder 205)
  - [1851-1900]
    - A new map of California by Charles Drayton Gibbes from his own and other recent surveys and explorations, 1852 (Folder 59)
    - Plaza in Los Angeles City, Calif., 1856-12-01 (Folder 13)
    - Map of the city of Los Angeles showing the confirmed limits surveyed in August 1857 by Henry Hancock, 1857-08 (Folder 5)
    - Map of Central California from 37th to 40th deg. north lat.: showing various railroad routes projected or in progress together with a practicable route to enter the state with a Pacific railroad, 1860 (Folder 87)
    - Map of the public land [in the] states and territories constructed from the public surveys and other official sources in the General Land Office, 1865 (Folder 51)
    - Map of the Union Pacific Railway Eastern Division and connections, from the Mississippi River to San Francisco, 1867 (Folder 55)
    - Plat of the Rancho Muscupiabe, finally confirmed to Miguel White, 1867-11 (Folder 99)
    - Map showing the lands of the Tide Land Reclamation Company, 1869 (Folder 132)
    - San Francisco Peninsula, 1869 (Folder 71)
    - City of Los Angeles, Los Angeles County, Cal., 1871 (Folder 8)
    - Map of a portion of Los Angeles County showing the Abel Stearns' ranches: La Habra, Los Coyotes, San Juan Cajon, Las Bolsas, La Bolsa Chica, 1873-05 (Folder 94)
    - Map of the county of San Luis Obispo, California, 1874 (Folder 100)
    - Map of the Ranchos Centinela and Sausal Redondo, 1875 (Folder 105)
    - Rand McNally and Co.'s indexed map of California and Nevada, 1877 (Folder 134)
    - New transcontinental map of the Pacific R.R. and routes of overland travel to Colorado, Nebraska, the Black Hills, Utah, Idaho, Nevada, Montana, California and the Pacific Coast, 1877 (Folder 55)
    - Lands of the Los Angeles City Water Co., in Los Angeles City, Cal., 1877 (Folder 6)
    - Bird's-eye-view of Los Angeles, California, 1877 (Folder 60)
    - Map of the exterior boundaries and official locations of Ranchos San Jose addition to San Jose and Azusa, 1877-04 (Folder 12)
    - Guide map of the city of San Francisco: compiled from the official surveys and engraved expressly for Langley's San Francisco Directory, 1878 (Folder 71)
    - A portion of Los Angeles as seen from the Ninth Street tract; and, Map of the ninth street tract, 1880 (Folder 36)
    - Railway map of the Weekly Call, 1880 (Folder 50)
    - Bird's eye view of Coronado Beach, San Diego Bay and city of San Diego, Cal. in distance, 1880 (Folder 60)
    - Map of the Central Pacific Railroad, Southern Pacific Railroad, and connections, 1880 (Folder 83)
    - Map of the county of Los Angeles, California, 1881 (Folder 125)
    - Nuevo mapa de los estados de Sonora, Chihuahua, Sinaloa, Durango y territoria de la Baja California = New map of Sonora, Chihuahua, Sinaloa, Durango and Lower California, 1881 (Folder 205)
    - Map of the city of Los Angeles, California, 1884 (Folder 37)
    - Mining map of Inyo County, 1884 (Folder 92)
    - El Cajon Rancho and surrounding region, 1885 (Folder 105)
    - The unique map of California, 1885 (Folder 134)
    - Pasadena, Los Angeles County, Cal., 1885 (Folder 60)
    - Map of the subdivision of Rancho San Jose de Buenos Ayres and the town of Sunset, owned by [the] Los Angeles & Santa Monica Land & Water Co., 1887 (Folder 2)
    - Map showing subdivision of lands belonging to the Lankershim Ranch Land and Water Co.: being the east 1200 acres of the south half of Ranch Ex Mission of San Fernando, Los Angeles County, California, 1887-11 (Folder 93)
    - Map showing routes of the Pacific Coast Steamship Company, 1888 (Folder 57)
    - Bird's eye view of Placerville, Calif., 1888 (Folder 60)
    - Map of St. Louis and San Francisco R[ailwa]y and connections, 1889 (Folder 83)
    - San Buena Ventura, 1890 (Folder 60)
    - Map of a portion of San Bernardino and San Diego counties, showing the Bear Valley reservoir, its watershed, also the valleys where its waters are to be used, including the Alessandro and Perris irrigation districts, 1890 (Folder 99)
    - Cox and Sanders index map of Los Angeles City, 1896 (Folder 3)
    - Map of the city of Los Angeles, 1897: accompanying Maxwell's Los Angeles city directory and gazetteer of Southern California (Folder 108)
    - Official map of the county of Los Angeles, 1898 (Folder 131)
    - State of California, 1900 (Folder 134)
    - Commisioners' official railway map of California, completed to January 1st, 1900 (Folder 57)
    - Map of the Los Angeles-Pacific R.R., 1900 (Folder 96)
  - [1900s]
    - Map of Sausal Redondo Rancho, Centinela Rancho and part of Rancho La Ballona, 1901 (Folder 123)
    - Map of the sub-division of the Puente Crude Oil Co's lands, 1901-12-20 (Folder 93)
    - California political subdivisions maps showing senatorial, congressional, railroad, equalization, and assembly districts plus a map of San Francisco political subdivisions, 1902 (Folder 57)
    - Weber's township and county map of the states of California and Nevada compiled from the latest data available, 1902 (Folder 59)
    - Map of the city of Los Angeles, 1903 (Folder 18)
    - El Camino Real: outline map of California showing missions and principal settlements prior to secularization of the missions in 1834, 1903 (Folder 61)
    - Grazing lands, western United States: general location and area, 1905 (Folder 55)
    - Birdseye view of Casa Verdugo Villa tract, a sub-division of a portion of the old Rancho San Rafael, 1906 (Folder 105)
    - Map of Los Angeles and suburbs, 1906 (Folder 20)
    - Road map of the Bay counties: compiled from the latest and most accurate official data, 1907 (Folder 88)
    - Inglewood the hub city: map of Los Angeles County, Southwest, 1908 (Folder 121)
    - Map of part of San Francisco, California, April 18, 1908: showing buildings constructed and buildings under construction during two years after fire of April 18, 1906, 1908-04-18 (Folder 71)
    - Map of city and county of San Francisco, 1909 (Folder 71)
    - California, now or never! The new glory of the Golden State, map of the Sacramento Valley Irrigation Project, California, 1909-09-21 (Folder 88)
    - Lines of the Pacific Electric Railway in Southern California, 1912 (Folder 120)
    - Clason's map of California, 1913 (Folder 58)
    - Map of the city of Los Angeles, 1918 (Folder 21)
    - Map of a portion of the Agua Caliente Indian Reservation, Riverside County, California, 1919-02 (Folder 99)
    - Relief map of territory served by lines of [the] Pacific Electric Railway in Southern California; largest electric railway system in the world, 1920 (Folder 91)
    - City of Los Angeles: city limits as at end of year 1875, 1920 (Folder 94)
    - Maps of city of Los Angeles, 1923-01 (Folder 9)
    - The heart of Los Angeles, 1925 (Folder 31)
    - Los Angeles as it appeared in 1871, when the Germain Seed & Plant Co. was established, 1929 (Folder 4)
    - Map showing territory annexed to the city of Los Angeles, California, 1935 (Folder 42)
    - California, the golden state, 1938 (Folder 133)
    - Los Angeles County drainage area, California: San Gabriel River improvement: Whittier Narrows flood control basin: base map of land to be acquired, 1948-12 (Folder 132)
    - City of Los Angeles: incorporated under American law April 4, 1850, 1950 (Folder 125)
    - A map of the marked historical sites of California: compiled from the official registrations of the California State Department of Natural Resources, 1952 (Folder 61)
    - A map of the missions, presidios, pueblos, and some of the more interesting ranchos of Spanish California: together with the routes of the principal land explorations therein, 1956-12 (Folder 134)
    - California, 1967 (Folder 59)
- Southern California and beach cities., 10 items. (Folder 120)
- Southern California and beach cities, including Rancho Ballona, Redondo and Playa del Rey., 10 items. (Folder 121)
- Southern California and beach cities, including Rancho Ballona, Redondo and Playa del Rey., 10 items. (Folder 122)
- Southern California and beach cities, including Rancho Ballona, Redondo and Playa del Rey., 10 items. (Folder 123)
- Southern California and beach cities, including Rancho Ballona, Redondo and Playa del Rey., 10 items. (Folder 124)
- Los Angeles., 10 items. (Folder 125)
- Los Angeles., 10 items. (Folder 126)
- Los Angeles., 8 items. (Folder 127)
- Los Angeles., 10 items. (Folder 128)
- Los Angeles., 10 items. (Folder 129)
- Los Angeles, Azusa, Venice., 6 items. (Folder 130)
- Miscellaneous California., 11 items. (Folder 131)
- Miscellaneous California., 10 items. (Folder 132)
- Miscellaneous California. (Includes Jo Mora California poster.), 11 items. (Folder 133)
- California., 11 items. (Folder 134)
- Northern California., 13 items. (Folder 135)
- Northern California., 12 items. (Folder 136)
- Southern California., 11 items. (Folder 137)
- Southern California., 17 items. (Folder 138)
- Cataloged maps. See shelf list for location and description. items. (Folder 139)
- California Geological Survey materials, Eastern Sierra region., 11 items. (Folder 140)
- California Geological Survey materials, Eastern Sierra region. (Folder 141)
- San Francisco Bay area., 11 items. (Folder 142)
- San Francisco Bay area., 10 items. (Folder 143)
- San Francisco Bay area., 4 items. (Folder 144)
- Northern California tract maps, subdivisions, lots for sale, ranchos, etc., 10 items. (Folder 145)
- Northern California tract maps, lots for sale, subdivisions, ranchos, etc. (Box 146, Box 147)
- Northern California (mostly San Francisco Bay area) tract maps, subdivisions and ranchos., ca. 1860-1880.; 10 items. (Folder 148)
- Northern California (mostly San Francisco Bay area) tract maps, subdivisions and ranchos., ca. 1860-1880.; 10 items. (Folder 149)
- Northern California (mostly San Francisco Bay area) tract maps, subdivisions and ranchos., ca. 1860-1880.; 10 items. (Folder 150)
- Northern California (mostly San Francisco Bay area) tract maps, subdivisions and ranchos., ca. 1860-1880.; 10 items. (Folder 151)
- Northern California (mostly San Francisco Bay area) tract maps, subdivisions and ranchos., ca. 1860-1880.; 10 items. (Folder 152)
- Northern California (mostly San Francisco Bay area) tract maps, subdivisions and ranchos., ca. 1860-1880.; 10 items. (Folder 153)
- Northern California (mostly San Francisco Bay area) tract maps, subdivisions and ranchos., ca. 1860-1880.; 10 items. (Folder 154)
- Northern California (mostly San Francisco Bay area) tract maps, subdivisions and ranchos., ca. 1860-1880.; 18 items. (Folder 155)
- Arizona., 9 items. (Folder 156)
- New Mexico oil fields., 8 items. (Folder 157)
- New Mexico., 8 items. (Folder 158)
- North Carolina., 1779-1897.; 27 items. (Folder 159)
- South Carolina., 1779-1873.; 20 items. (Folder 160)
- South Carolina., 1704-1860.; 14 items. (Folder 161)
- North Carolina and South Carolina., 1775-1875.; 15 items. (Folder 162)
- North Carolina and South Carolina., 1676-1891.; 28 items. (Folder 163)
- Arkansas and Louisiana., 1774-1877.; 21 items. (Folder 164)
- Florida., 1775-1949.; 19 items. (Folder 165)
- Virginia., 1754-1932.; 20 items. (Folder 166)
- Virginia and Washington, D.C., 1769-1863.; 5 items. (Folder 167)
- Alabama and Mississippi., 1825-1875.; 24 items. (Folder 168)
- Tennessee., 1795-1865.; 6 items. (Folder 169)
- Kentucky., 1810-1952.; 27 items. (Folder 170)
- Tennessee and Kentucky., 1823-1890.; 22 items. (Folder 171)
- Georgia., 1779-1927.; 14 items. (Folder 172)
- Southern States., 1799-1915.; 20 items. (Folder 173)
- Southern States., 1755-1878.; 12 items. (Folder 174)
- Civil War. Sherman's March, Chancellorsville, Gettysburg, and Peninsula Campaign., 1862-1867.; 10 items. (Folder 175)
- Civil War., 10 items. (Folder 176)
- Civil War. Including, Michler Series (The War Department Office of the Chief of Engineers. Military maps illustrating the operations of the Potomac and James, 1864-1865....) and Antietam and Harper's Ferry., 1864-1867.; 15 items. (Folder 177)
- Civil War., 21 items. (Folder 178)
- Civil War. War Department, Chickamauga and Chatanooga National Park Commission., 1901-1902. (Folder 179)
- Hawaii, Nevada and Texas., 1810-1933.; 29 items. (Folder 180)
- Oregon and Washington., 1843-1948.; 22 items. (Folder 181)
- Nevada, Colorado, Montana, Utah and Wyoming., 1861-1952.; 14 items. (Folder 182)
- Western United States., 1800s.; 5 items. (Folder 183)
- United States., ca. 1844-1920.; 20 items. (Folder 184)
- United States., 1768-1936.; 35 items. (Folder 185)
- United States., 1806-1953.; 14 items. (Folder 186)
- North America, Greenland, Atlantic., 1740-1884.; 30 items. (Folder 187)
- North America., 1790-1952.; 31 items. (Folder 188)
- South America., 1750-1874.; 25 items. (Folder 189)
- Mexico, Central America and Caribbean. Includes Amelia Earhart map., 1595-1933.; 29 items. (Folder 190)
- Mexico, Central America, Caribbean., 1626-1945.; 10 items. (Folder 191)
- Northern and Central Atlantic States., ca. 1750-1960.; 34 items. (Folder 192)
- Midwestern United States., ca. 1850-1960.; 34 items. (Folder 193)
- Russia and USSR., ca. 1650-1947.; 37 items. (Folder 194)
- Russia and USSR., ca. 1650-1947.; 20 items. (Folder 195)
- Australia and Pacific Islands., ca. 1630-1903.; 10 items. (Folder 196)
- World Maps., 1529-1927.; 26 items. (Folder 197)
- Asia Minor, Middle East and Orient., ca. 1700-1906.; 34 items. (Folder 198)
- World Maps., 1516-1939.; 28 items. (Folder 199)
- Great Britain and Ireland., 1574-1933.; 23 items. (Folder 200)
- Western Europe., 1639-1946.; 32 items. (Folder 201)
- Africa and India., ca. 1700-1880.; 14 items. (Folder 202)
- Central America., 1852.; 8 items. (Folder 203)
- Cataloged maps. (Box 204, Folder 205, Box 206)
  - Official map of Los Angeles County, comp. under insructions and by order of the Board of Superintendents .... San Francisco, Schmidt Label & Lithograph Company., c. 1888.; * G4363 L8 1888; Cf. Robinson 52. Poor Condition Cracked along middle; edges flaking; mounted on linen; bottom badly cracked and flaking.; Colored map. 182 × 153cm. Scale 1: 1.5 miles.
  - Rueger's map of greater Los Angeles, Los Angeles., 1904.; * G4364 L875 1904; Cf. Robinson 52. Mounted on linen; edges cracked; very dirty on bottom 12.; Colored map. 174 × 162cm. Scale 1: 600'.; Insets: Marginal map of North East corner of the city; index to subdivisions. Note: The $ in 1904 is hand-lettered and pasted over another number; also, corrections and additions have been made. (Roll 211)
  - Official map of Yuba County California Co. & drawn from official surveys. San Francisco, Britton & Company., 1861.; * G4363 Y8 1861; Cracking all over under varnish (?) covering.; Colored map. 135 × 94cm. Scale 1: 1 mile. (Roll 217)
    General note
    Note: Approved and declared official county map.
  - Map of the county of Los Angeles, California Co. ... by J.H. Wildy and A.J. Stahlberg. n.p., Julius Bien Lithograph., 1877.; * G4363 L8 1877a; Cf. Robinson 47. Cracking; mounted on linen; varnished (?).; Colored map. 128 × 117cm. Scale 1: 2,640'. (Roll 220)
    Note: Adopted by Board of Supervisors August 7, 1877.
    Gift of Miss Helena Fairbanks.